Francllin Félix Rios

Brasilian, single, 25 years old

Rua Antônio Dias Martins, N. 109, Matatu – Salvador – BA

public_profile

PROFILE

Professional with 6 years of IT experience, ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management, Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL) and Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC). I am a visionary and communicative person who is willing to actively and productively look for resolutions for the company needs. I have the objective of competently develope the tasks of software test planning, that are: Creation of test methodologies, test cases, test plans, use cases, automation tests, execution and monitoring of Tests. I also plan on working in the quality and processes field.

SKILL SET:

Functional Testing, Non-functional Testing, Manual Testing, Test Planning, Test case, Integration Testing, Regression Testing, Usability Testing, Test Management, Smoke Testing, Exploratory Testing, Experience on test requirements, Defect Tracking, Bug Tracking, Acceptance Testing, Behavior Driven Development and Inspection documentation, Database Testing (SQL Server, Neo4j, Postgresql) and Test Automation (Selenum IDE, WebDriver + Cucumber, JUnit).

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree: Systems Development and Analysis.

Institution: Faculdade Maurício de Nassau

Graduate Program: MBA in Project Management.

Institution: Estácio (FIB) Conclusion: November, 2016

EXPERIENCE

2016 - eCGlobal Solutions – (Current)

Post: Test Analyst

Activities:

- Planning (activities estimation), elaboration of quality documents and tests, dissemination of knowledge to the project team, report of project status to the management team.
- Revision of requirements documentation;
- Creation of test cases;
- Tests performing Functional tests, Load test, System test, Stress test, Regression test, Reverse test engineering and Acceptance test;
- Automated testing with (Selenium IDE and Selenium IDE Executor RC), Jmeter and WebStressTester.
- Planning, monitoring and quality control using the good practices of PMBOK 5.
- Creation and reverse engineering of documents: (Use case, Class diagram, interface description, message documents and business rule documents)
- Dissemination of the use of the Rup and UML methodology for requirements management.
- Creation of user stories using BDD (Behavior Driven Development) methodology.
- Dissemination of the use of Quality Management with Agile methodology (Scrum).
- Deployment and execution with WebDriver + Cucumber (BDD) test.

2015 - 2016 Secretarias da Educação do Estado da Bahia - X-Testing

Post: Test Analyst Jr III

Activities:

• Execution of software tests to assure the quality of the systems developed for the Education Department of the State of Bahia. Experience executing static analysis of source code, load test, system test, stress test, regression test, reverse test engineering, integration test and acceptance test. Experience on searching for anomalies and nonconformities in the semantics of systems using automated tools in the process, such as: The Mantis Bugtracker to report bugs, Jmeter, Selenium IDE and Testelink.

2014 – 2015 - Capgemini

Post: Test Analyst Jr

Activities:

Assurance, with software testing execution, of the quality of the system developed by the
companies: SIIBC, CAIXA Internet Banking and CAIXA mobile banking. Experience in
executing static analysis of source code looking for anomalies and nonconformities in
code semantics. Use of automated tools in the processes, such as GID, JIRA and
MANTIS for bug reports.

 Manual exploratory tests to validate the system information with the information applied to pre-established business rules, requirements document, class diagrams and all development project documentation.

•

- Control and identification of nonconformities, aiming to keep the quality indexes of the system always up to date. Use of risk assessment techniques to provide advanced support in the decision-making process.
- Responsible for guaranteeing the quality of the system in homologation and production
 environments by reading and interpreting the information of the development project
 documentation. Also, responsible for managing the documentation for each version of the
 system that is released, keeping the operations sector informed and thus ensuring that the
 system has, in addition, qualified support and positive feedback.
- Elaboration of Software Test Plans, situation list and simulation of test cases based on user stories. Maintenance of test cases database with TestLink and RedMine tools, validation of business rules and databases.
- Responsible for elaborating test guides to ensure the efficiency of the homologation process of new functionalities. Homologation of new developments in order to ensure the stability and correct functioning of new projects. Creation and ministration of test and quality indicators in order to measure the level of excellence of the developments carried out by the Development team.
- Elaboration and execution of exploratory tests for mobile platforms (Android, IOS and Windows phone).

2012 – 2014 - Mac engenharia e Instalações Ltda

Activities:

- Dell server administration: (domain, production, bank (SQL server 2008), test-approval).
- Server administration: (Terminal service).
- Firewall server administration: (Uniconet).
- Assembly and maintenance of servers, desktops and notebooks.
- Planning, drafting and implementing network infrastructure projects.
- Elaboration and implementation of security policy.
- Management, development and implementation of Virtualization project with Hyper-V.

- Assembly and maintenance of 802.3 ethernet networks (Wired Network) and wireless networks.
- Monitoring Windows Server 2008 R2 environment backup (CobianBackup).
- Trend Micro worry-free business security.
- Administration of Windows Server 2008 R2, Active Directory (AD), DNS GPO, DHCP, and File Server.
- Virtual Private Network (VPN) Management and Deployment Hamachi LogMeIn.
- Maintenance and repair of telephone lines.
- Printer management and maintenance (network).
- Support to Internal and External Clients.
- Internal Support to the Senior ERP System (sapiens, Vetor, Ronda punto, Seguridad y Medicina).
- E-mail administration and platform domain: (Locaweb).
- Creation of test cases, software exploratory test and automated test execution.

PROJECTS:

• Implementation and management of the Internal Active Directory (OpenFire - Spark).

Company: Macengenharia e instalação LTDA.

• Implementation and management of Open Source Service Desk system, modeled on ITIL - (GLPI).

Portfolio: http://www.macengenharia.com/helpdesk/

Company: Macengenharia e instalação LTDA.

• Implementation, development, testing and management of the HelpDesk system Human Resources - HR. (Ocomon)

Portfolio: http://www.macengenharia.com/helpdeskrh/

Company: Macengenharia e instalação LTDA.

• Development and testing of the cartridge management system. Portfolio: http://www.macengenharia.com/cartucho/sistema.php

Company: Macengenharia e instalação LTDA.

• Owncloud system deployment, private cloud file sharing system.Portfolio: 189.26.255.40/owncloud

Company: Macengenharia e instalação LTDA.

• Planning, execution and preparation of software testing. System: SIIBC, CAIXA Internet Banking, CAIXA mobile banking Company: Capgemini.

• Planning, execution and elaboration of automated software testing. System: All the systems from the Secretary of Educaton of Bahia (SEC)

Company: Secretaria da Educação da Bahia.

• Planning, execution and elaboration of automated software testing.

System: All systems from eCGlobal, Rede Globo, HBO and Turner.

Company: eCGlobal solutions.

CERTIFICATIONS:

• ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management License number: 5408680.20419613

• CTFL – Certified Tester Foundation Level

Instituição: ISTQB

License number:15-CTFL-04596-BR

Scrum Fundamentals Certified

License number: 82814

QUALIFICATIONS AND PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Tools:

- Mantis Bugtracker
- Redmine
- Testlink
- Tortoise SVN
- Selenium
- SQL developer
- Toad for Oracle
- JIRA
- GID
- Jmeter
- Enterprise Architect (EA)
- Vivifyscrum

Databases:

- Mysql
- SQL Server 2008.
- Neo4J
- Postgresql

Programing languages for tests:

PHP

- HTML
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Java

OTHER INFORMATIONS

- Available for travelling.

 Driver's license for motorcycle and ride vehicles.